Aman Saxena

Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh





amansaxena106@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack .NET Developer with over 2 years of experience in C# and .NET technologies and frameworks Team player with strong oral and written communication skills and problem-solving aptitude. Proactiv and passionate to work on challenging assignments that will help provide job satisfaction and my professional growth.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020 **PSIT COE**

B. Tech -8.1 - CSE Kanpur, India

Key Skills

Python/C#/EF-Core

. Programing skill

MSSQL/Oracle/SSIS/SSMS

EXPERIENCE

Infosys Oct 2020 - PRESENT Senior System Engineer Mohali, India

- · C# and ASP.Net Developer, MVC Developer. Works in Scrum, Waterfall and Test-Driven Development environment.
- · Worked on SSIS Packages.
- Develop logics for a new functionalities and requirement.
- · Works on various client needs. Provided end-to-end delivery to the client.
- · Full Stack Developer- Develop and enhance database functionalities and back-end functionalities.
- Debug any known features and test new code to ensure proper functionality.
- · Resolved client issues by establishing workarounds and solutions to debug and create defect fixes.
- Troubleshoot, tested and remedied issues before software deployment.
- · Participated in team meetings and provided input on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Automate the full process of daily monitoring in project alone.

INTERNSHIPS

Infosys Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

System Engineer Trainee

Mysore, India

- · Worked on applications like Visual Studio 2017, MS SQL and postman to develop our project.
- Designed front-end page for a website using HTML, Javascript and CSS.
- Designed functions to run according to given specifications in C#
- Developed database to store user information, product information and run query to provide desired results or data.
- Developed a mini project as a Scrum master of 4 member Team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, Python, SQL, MySql, Javascript.

Developer Tools: VS Code, MS SQL Server, Postman, SSMS, SSIS.

Technologies/Frameworks: ASP.NET CORE, MVC,

ACHIEVEMENTS

• 5 Star coder in Python Basics in HackerRank Platform.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/0b7b394a0822

• 5 Star coder in Problem Solving using Python in HackerRank Platform.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/af45ab6bfa25

Projects

Projects			
Title	E-Library	Venue Automation	Travel Buddy
Team Size	Self	4 Member	4 Member
Duration	2 Week	2 Weeks	1 Month
Platform Used	Servlet, JSP, Html, Oracle	Python	.Net, EF-Core,
			MsSql
Role Played	Full-Stack Developer	Logics Developer	Scrum master
Description	Online learning web-app for students in their studies.	Book a venue online using this application.	help travellers to find all services in one Application.

STRENGTHS

Proactive

. Leadership Skills